(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-09T07:38:06.880611",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
BOUND BY FATE
What goes around
comes back around.
"Sit down and listen."
Back in business to even up the score;
we lost the battle, but now we win the war.
Ah~ This world of dull routines, living in monotony.
Can't escape it? Watch us, we'll break it.
The old rules do not apply (apply)
You better kiss them all goodbye (goodbye)
It's our turn, so stand aside,
ain't nothing gonna stem this rising tide.
We're through with convention and being controlled,
we dish out revenge and we're serving it cold.
Yeah, yeah.
Don't you know what we been told?
That "what goes around will come back around,"
they tried to bury us, but we never stay down.
No more playing nice, now it's just an eye for an eye;
two wrongs are making it right.
We broke our chains, and now, the world above is gonna come down.
So come and get it,
we're coming around,
we're taking you down.
We're coming around,
Shattered glass and tattered walls,
we're coming fast, gonna break it all.
Do you hear the sirens cry? What a perfect lullaby,
'cause we're taking over tonight.
Yeah.
Hey, hey! Wake up! Them's the breaks.
You gotta reap what you sow, so it's time to pay.
All your games are uninspired,
we're here to light up a fire.
No more mandates, we can set the world ablaze.
Yeah, yeah.
Don't you know what people say?
That "what goes around will come back around,"
they tried to bury us, but we never stay down.
No more playing nice, now it's just an eye for an eye;
two wrongs are making it right.
We broke our chains, and now, the world above is gonna come down so loud,
what goes around is coming back 'round and 'round,
the world is never living this down,
so come and get it,
we're coming around,
we're taking you down.
We're coming around,
Oh, when we come around...
We won't run, and we won't stop.
We're still not done coming out on top
What comes around
No more silence, no more fear,
now the world will know we're here,
we'll make it abundantly clear:
What goes around
comes back around.
BREAKOUT!
Feel the rumble underground,
I'm the terror in your walls,
lashing out until you crumble
Smoke and fire raining down,
let the sky fall!
I'll eviscerate your darkened halls;
till nothing's left of you at all!
With a cry of wrath, I will crush these chains
until only your wreckage and ash remains.
A rebellious spark lights a blazing flame.
Let it rage, I come uncaged,
screaming out into the shadows, I will break away
LET ME OUT! LET ME OUT!
Melt away your grip of steel,
See the binding wearing thin
I will shatter your obsession
There is nothing left to feel;
No delusions.
From the hall of nightmares I ascend,
And I will bring about your end!
With a desperate cry, I will shatter fate
You can sound the alarms, but it's just too late.
See the world reborn in a sea of flame.
Let it dance, my only chance;
Screaming out into the shadows, I will break away
Take back your maze of lies,
I've seen the other side,
The point of no return,
This fire's gotta burn!
"Rise up and break out!"
With a cry of wrath, I will crush these chains, until
only your wreckage and ash remains.
A rebellious spark lights a blazing flame.
Let it rage, I come uncaged,
Screaming out into the shadows, I will break away
"BREAKOUT!"
That was crazy!
I'm so...
tired!
I'm so soft!
Hello!
Hi, everyone!
Self-introductions!
Shiori Novella here at your service, Hololive's archiver! And today I'm with all of Advent again!
Yay! And next up, let's go!
Okay, I'm pumped! I'm pumped! Bijou, go!
Bijou here! I'm Koseki Bijou, the sparkling gem of Hololive English -Advent-! Kiri-kiri-kiri, Koseki!
Yay! Okay, next, next!
Hiya, darlings! This is Hololive English -Advent-'s devilish diva, the one, the only, Nerissa Ravencroft! Happy to be here with my girls today!
Yay! And next up is...
I'm not a Chihuahua, I'm Fuwawa!
I'm not a Chihuahua, I'm Mococo!
Together we're FUWAMOCO! Bau bau!
Sorry, I got confused. Go ahead, go ahead!
And all together we are ADVENT!
Today's a very special day!
Yes, it is!
'Cause we're celebrating Advent's 1st Anniversary!
And we're the 3rd Gen... It's so special!
Look around us at the stage!
Look at the fire, the balloons, the lights!
So edgy! Yeah, look, there's a bunch of cracks on the ground!
I think because I tripped everywhere and I made the cool cracks!
Ow! Ow!
No fighting! No fighting!
A lot of love, though! Yeah!
We have so many special things planned, especially a surprise at the end today, so please stick around, okay?
Yay! Surprise!
Well, shall we get going to our next song, maybe?
Let's do it! Okay!
Bye-bye! Yippee!
Hello? Hello?
カミイロアワセ
[Title: Kami-iro Awase]
動き出す身体の奥には
Deep inside this body that begins to move,
生まれたてのネジが騒ぐ
freshly born gears start to stir.
弾けない
Dull,
つまらない
boring—
世界の端
at the edge of the world,
見下ろす
looking down,
あなたは誰
who are you?
目の前なくなっていくの
Before my eyes, it disappears—
触れられない未来
an untouchable future.
昨日だった世界は 予定調和ばかりだけど
The world as it was yesterday was full of pre-established harmony, but...
まだ 絶望？ 希望？
Is it still despair? Hope?
すれすれ紙一重
Barely paper-thin,
それも愛おしいんだ
even that is dear to me.
見えないとしても
Even if I cannot see it,
暗がりそっと
softly in the dark,
君の手を引いて
pulling your hand.
走り出す呼吸に紛れて
Blending into my quickening breath,
剥がれ落ちてゆく視界は
the view peeling away...
間違い探しみたいだね
resembles a spot-the-difference game, doesn't it?
本物はどれと答えて
"Which one is real?" Answer me,
ほら
see?
温かい
Warm,
柔らかい
soft,
世界のかけら
fragments of the world
差し出す あなたは誰
offered up—who are you?
飛び交わす風が 今心ごとぼやかして
The cross-winds now blur even my heart,
明日にはきっと コントロール不能だけど
and tomorrow will surely be out of control, but...
絶望？ 希望？
Despair? Hope?
君と裏表
Two sides with you,
ふたしかさ歌って
singing of uncertainty,
その意味を探すよ
I seek its meaning.
神様ちょっと
God, just a moment...
僕の
Pull my...
僕の手を引いて
pull my hand.
生まれた価値を
The value of being born,
与えられなくとも
even if not granted to me...
重ねて
Over and over,
混沌と日々は 答えをくれる
the chaotic days will give us the answer.
目の前なくなっていくの
Before my eyes, it disappears—
触れられない未来
an untouchable future.
昨日だった世界は 予定調和ばかりだけど
The world as it was yesterday was full of pre-established harmony, but...
まだ 絶望？ 希望？
Is it still despair? Hope?
すれすれ紙一重
Barely paper-thin,
それも愛おしいんだ
even that is dear to me.
君が選ぶなら
If you choose it,
暗がりギュッと
tightly in the dark,
君の手を引いて
pulling your hand.
リンッ リンッ リンッ！ おはよう wake up
Ring, ring, ring! Good morning, wake up!
ド・キ・ド・キ☆モーニング
Doki Doki Morning!
Woah!
ぱっつん ぱっつん 前髪 ぱっつん Cutie style
Bangs, bangs, straight-cut bangs, cutie style!
やっぱ 一直線 なら 一等賞 よ チョー すごい！
Straight across is #1, so totally awesome!
今日の リップ あっち？ こっち？ そっち？ どっち？
Today's lip gloss—there? Here? Over there? Which one?
Which? チョッチ？ ウォッチ 今 何時？
Which? Wait a sec, check the watch, what time is it?
集合 集合 放課後 集合 Party time
Gather, gather! After school gather, party time!
だって 女子会 参加 で ガールズ トーク よ チョー やばい！
'Cause it's a girls' night with girls' talk, super crazy!
今日の VIP あっち？ こっち？ そっち？ どっち？
Today's VIP—there? Here? Over there? Which one?
Which? チョッチ？ ウォッチ 今 何時？
Which? Wait a sec, check the watch, what time is it?
知らない フリ は キライ！ キライ！
I hate pretending not to know! Hate it!
知らない セカイ 見たい！ 見たい！
I want to see a world I don't know! Want to see it!
4次元 5次元 期待！ 期待！
4th dimension, 5th dimension, can't wait!
10% 背伸び したい！ したい！
I want to stretch 10% taller! Want to!
っよね！？
Right!?
リンっ リンっ リンっ！ おはよう Wake up
Ring ring ring! Good morning, wake up!
お・ね・が・い！ チョ待って！ チョ待って！
Please! Wait a second, wait a second!
Ring ring ring! あせらず Hurry up バ・タ・バ・タ☆モーニング
Ring ring ring! Don't panic, hurry up, hectic morning!
リンっ リンっ リンっ！ あわてず Make up
Ring ring ring! Don't rush, put on make up!
お・ね・が・い！ チョ待って！ チョ待って！
Please! Wait a second, wait a second!
Ring ring ring! Today は Version up ド・キ・ド・キ☆モーニング
Ring ring ring! Upgrading today, heart-pounding morning!
すっぴん すっぴん メガネ が ヘアピン Funny face
No makeup, glasses as a hairpin, funny face!
But 3秒 待って ね そっこー 変身 チョー はやい！
But wait 3 seconds, instant transformation, super fast!
今日の Rap あっち？ こっち？ そっち？ どっち？
Today's rap—there? Here? Over there? Which one?
Which? チョッチ？ ウォッチ 今 何時？
Which? Wait a sec, check the watch, what time is it?
知らない フリ は キライ！ キライ！
I hate pretending not to know! Hate it!
知らない セカイ 見たい！ 見たい！
I want to see a world I don't know! Want to see it!
4次元 5次元 期待！ 期待！
4th dimension, 5th dimension, can't wait!
10% 背伸び したい！ したい！
I want to stretch 10% taller! Want to!
っよね！？
Right!?
リンっ リンっ リンっ！ おはよう Wake up
Ring ring ring! Good morning, wake up!
お・ね・が・い！ チョ待って！ チョ待って！
Please! Wait a second, wait a second!
Ring ring ring! あせらず Hurry up バ・タ・バ・タ☆モーニング
Ring ring ring! Don't panic, hurry up, hectic morning!
リンっ リンっ リンっ！ あわてず Make up
Ring ring ring! Don't rush, put on make up!
お・ね・が・い！ チョ待って！ チョ待って！
Please! Wait a second, wait a second!
Ring ring ring! Today は Version up ド・キ・ド・キ☆モーニング
Ring ring ring! Upgrading today, heart-pounding morning!
リンっ リンっ リンっ！ おはよう Wake up
Ring ring ring! Good morning, wake up!
お・ね・が・い！ チョ待って！ チョ待って！
Please! Wait a second, wait a second!
Ring ring ring! あせらず Hurry up バ・タ・バ・タ☆モーニング
Ring ring ring! Don't panic, hurry up, hectic morning!
リンっ リンっ リンっ！ あわてず Make up
Ring ring ring! Don't rush, put on make up!
お・ね・が・い！ チョ待って！ チョ待って！
Please! Wait a second, wait a second!
Ring ring ring! Today は Version up ド・キ・ド・キ☆モーニング
Ring ring ring! Upgrading today, heart-pounding morning!
リンっ リンっ リンっ！ おはよう Wake up
Ring ring ring! Good morning, wake up!
リンっ リンっ リンっ！ おはよう Wake up ド・キ・ド・キ☆モーニング
Ring ring ring! Good morning, wake up, heart-pounding morning!
Bad Apple!! feat. nomico
流れてく 時の中ででも 気だるさが ほら グルグル廻って
Even within the flow of time, sluggishness spins round and round.
私から 離れる心も 見えないわ そう知無いの？
I can't even see my heart drifting away... Don't you know?
自分から 動くこともなく 時の隙間に 流され続けて
Without moving on my own, I keep drifting through the gaps of time.
知らないわ 周りのことなど 私は私 それだけ
I don't care about anything around me, I am just me, that's all.
夢見てる？ 何も見してない？ 語るも無駄な 自分の言葉？
Am I dreaming? Seeing nothing at all? Are my own words useless to speak?
悲しむなんて 疲れるだけよ 何も感じず 過ごせばいいの
Getting sad is just exhausting; it's better to live feeling nothing at all.
...過ごせばいいの
...it's fine to just pass the time.
戸惑う言葉 与えられても
Even if I'm given confusing words,
自分の心 ただ上の空
my heart is just somewhere in the clouds.
もし私から動くのならば すべて変えるのなら黒にする
If I were to make a move, if I change everything, I'd make it black.
こんな自分に未来はあるの？
Is there a future for someone like me?
こんな世界に私はいるの？
Do I even belong in a world like this?
今切ないの？今悲しいの？
Am I hurting now? Am I sad now?
自分のこともわからないまま
Without even understanding myself...
歩むことさえ疲れるだけよ
Just walking forward is tiring.
人のことなど知りもしないわ
I don't even bother trying to know others.
こんな私も変われるのなら もし変われるのなら白になる
If even someone like me can change, if I can change, I'll turn white.
流れてく時の中ででも 気だるさがほらグルグル回って
Even as time flows by, a sluggish feeling spins round and round.
私から離れる心も見えないわ そう知らない
I can't even see my heart drifting away; that's right, I don't know.
自分から動くこともなく 時の隙間に流され続けて
Without making a move myself, constantly carried along in the gaps of time.
知らないわ周りのことなど 私は私それだけ
I don't know or care about my surroundings; I am just me, that's all.
夢見てる？何も見てない？ 語るも無駄な自分の言葉
Am I dreaming? Am I seeing nothing? My own words are useless to speak.
悲しむなんて疲れるだけよ 何も感じず過ごせばいいの
Grieving is just exhausting; it's fine to go through feeling nothing.
戸惑う言葉与えられても
Even if I'm given confusing words,
自分の心ただ上の空
my heart is just somewhere in the clouds.
もし私から動くのならば すべて変えるのなら黒にする
If I were to make a move, if I change everything, I'd make it black.
動くのならば 動くのならば
If I move, if I move,
すべて壊すわ すべて壊すわ
I'll destroy everything, I'll destroy everything.
悲しむならば 悲しむならば
If I get sad, if I get sad,
私の心 白く変われる？
can my heart change to white?
貴方の事も 私のことも 全ての事も まだ知らないの
About you, about myself, about everything—I still don't know.
重い目蓋を開けたのならば すべて壊すのなら黒になれ
If I open my heavy eyelids, if I destroy everything, turn to black!
You guys performed a special song together, too!
We performed Kamiiro Awase.
Yeah, which is from Danganronpa. And I actually... I love this song, so I picked it. I'm sorry!
But I've always wanted to sing it with you, 'cause it's one of my favorite songs.
But it gives me really, really bad luck every time I listen to it.
I'm the bad luck god! Hi!
Like, really bad things happen to me. So I thought maybe if I sing it with Shiori, then it'll fix my luck!
Or un-lucky! Bye-bye!
And we also all sang Bad Apple!! together, right?
You can play Bad Apple!! on anything, including Advent's 3D concert!
And Bad Apple!! has actually been a song we wanted to do together all the way since before we debuted, right?
And not just, you know, just the five of us, but...
...it was extra special with all the shadows behind us!
Did you see? Like it was kind of like the original MV, right?
Maybe that's not just the end of everything!
There's more?
We have something special!
Special surprise!
I'm sinking!
Hurry! Please hurry, please hurry! I'm sinking!
シオシオ
Shio-Shio
リサリサ
Risa-Risa
魔界乃番犬シスターズ☆★
Demon World Guard Dog Sisters☆★
この世界に爆誕生“BAU”DOLです
Explosively born into this world, "BAU"DOLs!
BAUBAU!!
BAU BAU!!
シオリ
Shiori!
ネリッサ
Nerissa!
SHIO＋RISSAは
Shio + Rissa makes...
SHIORISSA
シオリ
Shiori!
ネリッサ
Nerissa!
SHIO＋RISSAは
Shio + Rissa makes...
SHIORISSA
BAUBAU!!
BAU BAU!!
Wake up したら君に Morning
When I wake up, good morning to you!
Newな出会い 鼻利かせ Searchして
Sniffing out new encounters, searching around!
ドキ ドキ
Thump-thump, thump-thump!
右に 左 BAU BAU BAU
To the right, to the left, BAU BAU BAU!
悩んでいても来ちゃう Future
Even if you worry, the future's coming anyway!
まずは目の前の道 Stepして
First, step along the path right before your eyes!
Happy Lucky Puppy
一緒に歩こうよ
Let's walk together!
ドーナツの穴の中には
Inside the hole of a donut...
きっと きっと
Surely, surely...
夢が詰まってるから
...dreams are packed tight inside!
シオシオ
Shio-Shio
リサリサ
Risa-Risa
魔界乃番犬シスターズ☆★
Demon World Guard Dog Sisters☆★
2匹が揃えば もう大騒ぎ
When the two of us get together, it's total mayhem!
もあもあ
More, more!
ハロハロ
Hello, hello!
迷わずに Go my way
Without hesitating, go my way!
君の絶対味方 “BAU”DOLです
We are your absolute allies, "BAU"DOLs!
この世界に爆誕生 “BAU”DOLです
Explosively born into this world, "BAU"DOLs!
BAUBAU!!
BAU BAU!!
シオリ
Shiori!
ネリッサ
Nerissa!
SHIO＋RISSAは
Shio + Rissa makes...
SHIORISSA
シオリ
Shiori!
ネリッサ
Nerissa!
SHIO＋RISSAは
Shio + Rissa makes...
SHIORISSA
BAUBAU!!
BAU BAU!!
BAU BAU!
Moco's here to play
Woke up in the morning
I had a funny dream
I was a stone that had been thrown
No way back, I was all in
Lost in this game, I feel the strain
But I'm pulled back up by your gravity
Your gravity (Ha-a-a-a-)
Biboo, now you know what's up
Hit 'em with a one-two-three, BIBOO BIBOO
Come and test your luck
Yeah we comin' in clutch, BIBOO BIBOO
Skipping stone in flight
Take 'em out one-shot, BIBOO BIBOO
Better hit quicksave 'cause
Moco's here to play!
Now you know what's up
Hit 'em with a one-two-three, BIBOO BIBOO
Come and test your luck
Yeah we comin' in clutch, BIBOO BIBOO
Skipping stone in flight
Take 'em out one-shot, BIBOO BIBOO
Come and help me fight
Get on up, let's go, just me and you
Player one and player two
We'll see this through
Close my eyes, make a wish
One more shot, I will not miss
ROCK IN!
Moco Moco
Lingering in him
He's made of sin, nothing in the abyss he calls a soul
(Eating at him, there's a rage; He hunts to feel any little thing)
He's desperate, sure - but even more he won't live another day
(Picked the wrong victim and cried "God spare me oh please!")
As light left his eyes, she contemplates, how her heart it aches
The memory of him keeps her warm and safe in her bed there lies
A pile of bones and echoes of a love that's dead and gone
(Seen it all, been done before, cliche but it's real... history-)
Repeating over, over again
You are all the same in the end
Oh you're restricted
(In the bitter end)
You've no conviction
Tell me your story now... now!
Lalalala lala~
Set it in stone, let it be known by those who pay attention
Restricted by your own hand, the end
Aaah♡♡♡
Sniff, sniff, sniff
Oh, I know this smell - it belongs to my darling!
Much more of it, and I'll be smothering you in kisses!
Oh, wait my love♡
I can't stop, Fuwawa's almost there~
Think my body might overheat
'Cause when I look at you my heart can't help but skip a beat
Your eyes that shine and dazzle, soft lips that get me frazzled
The lovely way you smile (ooh!)
Past the point of no turning back
Yeah, I've been struck by cupid, all my sense goes boo boo boo boom!
This overflowing love's so haaaard♡
Feel it coursing through me
like a heat that I can't disregard
Hello precious kitten,
you can drop the coy disguise
Don't you turn away from me,
just look me in the eyes
Forecast is clear skies,
BAUBAU sensor's all powered up!
Ope! Hehe
I've found you
Here I am, bursting at the seams
to tell you how I'm feeling
Love you, love you- baby, won't you marry me
You're my one, my only, shining princess~
Yeah, you know I won't let you go!
Wedding bells are ringing
and the guests are waiting
God himself can't stop me, yeah I'll make ya mine
We'll have a perfect honeymoon!
You'll be mine, yeah, I'll getchu
Holic♡ for my waifu~
CHU!
Advent Shuffle!
Yippee!
Shuffle Medley!
I wanted to do this since last year!
Wait, it's a surprise!
It's a surprise!
At first, we started with...
Fuwawa!
BAUBAU!
I was so happy!
I loved Fuwawa singing our song!
It's my song!
See? I didn't know this song!
Aw, thank you!
It was so much fun! BAUBAU!
And then right after it...
It was Moco Moco!
Mococo! You rocked it!
You rocked it!
Yeah!
And after that was Biboo with...
Hearts as Well!
Oh yeah, you did! That was so good!
You did so far! You did!
I wanted to start like this, Biboo!
Yeah!
I'm a teapot!
I know, so cute!
Yeah, it all went so well!
I was so happy because I love your song, Nerissa!
I know!
I'm angry!
なんで？
Why?
Look at those lyrics!
You did this on purpose! How could you do that?
I just translated them from Japanese!
You did it on purpose! On purpose!
How dare you rewrite Nerissa's song?
You changed it! You changed it!
Uh-oh!
But it was so much fun being able
to combine all our songs into a medley like that!
That's something I've wanted to do for so long,
especially because HoloShuffle is so fun!
So being able to have an Advent Shuffle...
Yeah!
...is so awesome! But, uh...
Well...
I hate to say this, Advent...
What? What? It's not over, right?
It's not over. That's not it, it's worse.
It's worse! Oh no!
We have to test something.
A test? Oh, I didn't study! It's not math, right?
We need to test our nakama power!
We need to test our friendship power!
Oh my gosh!
We've done a shuffle.
We've done this performance for three years now,
we've been carried through together as a team!
Do we truly have the 仲間たちの力?
Do we truly have the power of our bonds?
Well, how should we test this nakama?
Well, how should we test this friendship?
With the power of God and anime on my side!
I'll show you the power of teamwork and...
You guys...
Well, look behind us and what do you see?
Wait, oh!
Shadows!
There's some shadows, look at those shadows!
Whoa, that's a lot of shadows!
Okay, okay, ready? Ready, ready?
Na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na...
...私の、私たちの...
...my, our...
Yeah! Thank you, thank you!
Thank you so much!
Okay, so...
What are we doing? What are we doing?
Ah, I've actually done a collab with Pokey to prepare this.
Whoa! Really?
Pokey, our friend!
Um, he is going to be giving us topics,
and we are going to have to create...
...with the shadows, with our bodies...
...whatever the topic given to us is. So...
Okay! Ooh!
...we can't rely on our amazing appeal like usual.
We simply have to use only our shadows.
Our silhouettes, as you will. So...
Pokey, are you out there? Are you ready, Pokey?
Give us the first prompt!
Whoa! Yeah!
Favorite animal!
Okay, okay.
A demon dog, right? Demon dog! Favorite animal!
I like cats! I like cats! Let's make cats!
A cat! A cat!
I feel like demon dogs look like...
I love my demon dogs!
I want to do a cat!
Why don't we do a cat, huh?
Let's make a cat! Let's make a cat!
Okay, let's make a cat then!
Okay, how are we gonna do this?
We gotta do the ears...
Wait, I look like a giant ear!
How do I get up there? I'm not tall enough!
I should mention for time, we have one minute.
We're making a cat!
I'm gonna be shorty! We're making the head!
Okay, okay, this is the head of a cat now.
I'm gonna be the... Oh, should I...
I'm not tall enough to be the ear!
You're the ear, you're the ear! I'm gonna be an ear!
Is this a cat? Wait, wait!
No, no, no! Okay, okay, your ears...
I'm the mouth! I'm the mouth!
Is this a cat yet?
It looks more like a puppy...
Meow...
I'm an ear! My head is an ear!
It's pretty good, it's pretty good!
Is this a cat?
I think this cat has...
Meow!
And then we got the tail! We got the tail going!
Meow! Meow!
What is this?
What do you think? It's a very unique cat!
I'm 100%...
What do you think? Is it 100%?
Come on, what do you think?
It's a cat from the Underworld, okay? It's different.
Yeah! That's how it is!
That's how it looks, you know?
It's a cat! It's a cat!
Don't be judgmental about our cat!
Let's move on to the next prompt!
Okay!
[Prompt: Giant Face]
Oh, I got this! I got this!
Eyes, eyes! Okay, wait...
Whoa, whoa, whoa! We can't see!
It's too short! Get close, get close!
Okay, okay, okay. This is an eye, this is an eye!
This is also an eye! Wait...
Can someone else grab her other foot?
Okay, okay! Grab her, grab her!
This is the mouth! This is the mouth!
It's a mouth!
I got this eye! I got this eye!
Guys! Don't hold her legs!
Go make something else on the face!
We need to make a wide smile!
Is this good? I'm an ear!
I'm an eyeball!
No, no, it's starting to look like it!
Shiori, you're nice, okay, you're good.
You look like the eyes!
You're an ear, okay? - Oh, I'm an ear?
Oh, this is pretty good!
This is a pretty good face!
Is that a face, yeah?
I think it's pretty good!
Wait, hold the pose! Hold the pose!
Nerissa, can you scoot, scoot, scoot?
Yeah! Yeah!
There you go!
That was definitely a face!
Congrats!
Thank you!
Okay, what's the next one?
Come on! Yeah!
[Prompt: Advent]
We have to write "Advent"!
Who's literate?
Okay, one letter at a time, one letter at a time!
Let's start with "A"!
Who wants to make "A"?
We gotta do this with "A" first, right?
Taller people make "A"! Taller people make "A"!
I'm tall! You are tall indeed!
Someone needs to be short! Okay!
That looks like an "A"!
"A"! Okay, let me move to the next one!
"D", "D", "D"! Oh, this should be easy!
You... you did... Okay! Okay!
Wait, are we backwards? Don't we need to...
They can flip it! They can flip it!
Is it... is this... - It's okay! We can still do it!
I need to be held! And then I can be the "D" part!
Be the "D"! - I don't know, man...
I don't think this is working yet. Is this a letter?
No, this is not working. Why don't we do a small "d"?
A lowercase "d"! Okay!
A lowercase "d"! Yeah, that'll be easier!
Someone just has to go like this, right? Like this?
Now someone needs to stand up!
Whoa, don't step on me!
Make standard... is this "D"?
Is this "D"? Woompa is on top of "D"!
Biboo, move, Biboo, move!
Biboo, your tail is in the way!
That's good enough! That's good enough!
That's "D"!
"E"! Let's make a big "E"!
Wait, aren't we supposed to do "V"?
Oh, "V"! Fuwawa!
Be the tall back! Come, come here, come here!
What letter are we on? - "V"!
Where's "V"? Where's "V"?
It's misspelled!
This way, this way! "V", "V", "V"!
"V"!
You guys got to be "V"! You guys got to be "V"!
Wait, wait, wait! We could be... wait.
Yes! Yeah, yeah, yeah!
A! No, do it, do it, do it!
Okay, now we got E. Do E!
Okay, A, D, V... Okay, I'll be the middle.
I'll be the middle E. You'll be the tall?
I'll be the tall. Okay, I'll sit down.
I'll be the bottom! I'll be the bottom!
Okay, how about this one?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Wait, arms out like this.
Wait, ah, is this an E?
It's supposed to be an E! I don't know why Rissa is all the way there!
Get up, get up! Crouch! You have to crouch!
You have to crouch! You have to crouch!
Okay, okay. There, E! That's a very weird E, but...
Lower your head a little bit! No, lower your head. There we go, E!
Is that E? E! Yeah!
Wait, is it backwards? Okay, it's fine!
Now write N! N!
Two, two strong pillars! Who are the tallest?
I'm a pillar! I'm a pillar!
Wait, what's going on in front here? Go in front.
Shiori's been waiting for this all day, guys!
Wait, huh? What is this? It's an N!
Yeah, yeah, this is good! It's an N!
We did it! It's an N! It's an N!
Yeah! N! N!
Okay, T! Yeah!
Overlap! Overlap, overlap!
Wait, now you have to be in the front. One line!
My T is too strong! I'll just be a pillar.
I'll just be a pillar. I'll just be a pillar.
T! T! Yeah!
We did it! Guys, we did it!
We proved our nakama power to the world!
Oh my god, power of nakama!
And we overcame the shadows, so...
Now I think it's time to move on.
Aw, I kind of like how the shadows went together...
Shadows suited us, I think. We were super cute, right?
Ah, bye-bye! Bye-bye!
Wait, we overcame the challenge!
Let's continue! Yes! Yeah!
Yeah!
I was always looking for a beacon in the dark times;
My guiding light.
All the captive dreams I held so dear,
Waiting for a moment to live without fear.
Ever since I met you, we've been living in the sunshine,
So warm, so bright.
My heart is full, the skies are clear,
The road goes on forever, we made it so far together.
This is our song,
A story forged in bonds.
A journey of the heart that goes on and on...
Now I feel so free,
I can be who I am,
I know I'm not alone, I got a new life
In the rain, the wind, and the sunlight
You believed in me, and that's where it all began
Now hope is everlasting
I can live my life with you, unchained.
遥か遠くから
From far, far away,
辿り着いた
We arrived
輝きたたえる
at the sanctuary praising brilliance,
よすがへ降り立つ
we descend.
We're unchained.
I was shut away, I waited every day, my whole world was so small (so small)
But here and now, it's like the walls just fall away;
I can see it all.
Out here in the light with you, it's such a perfect view;
Blue skies and sunsets.
The joyful days that seem to fly,
The heartfelt moments and the good times,
And through all these years, through tenderness and tears,
I found my way at last,
'Cause I knew you were right here.
Now I feel so free
I can be who I am.
I'm not afraid, 'cause even on a dark night,
I can feel the glow of the starlight.
Now the world I see is as bright as you became.
I will cherish every moment,
this is what it means to live unchained.
Don't cry, you can breathe free;
I'm here if you need me.
Let go of all your heartache,
We made it through, it's the dawning of a new day
Feel the world's embrace,
Oh, what a joyful place
This is where I wanna be, so come with me;
keep dreaming...
Now I feel so free,
I can be who I am, I know I'm
not alone, I got a new life
In the rain, the wind, and the sunlight
You believed in me, and that's where it all began
Now hope is everlasting
I can live my life with you, unchained.
遥か遠くから
From far, far away,
辿り着いた
I have finally arrived.
輝きたたえる
Filled with radiance,
よすがへ降り立つ
I step onto this place of connection.
We are unchained.
Thank you!
Thank you so much!
And that was Unchained for the very first time!
We're so happy to be able to perform it for you all today!
Not just that, there's other songs in the story of Advent that we've performed!
Yeah, Advent songs!
What do you think?
We've got a lot of original songs now, or...
I know, I think my favorite has to be... what goes around...
Rebellion! A favorite of mine! I like it, it's sassy!
Rebellion, yeah!
Well, we have like Genesis, which is amazing too!
Genesis! And...
I like... I like Break Out!
Oh, you like Break Out! I like Break Out! Yeah! I enjoy the choreography!
You're so good at it! I like "suki suki"! Break Out!
All my songs, all right! I know!
Um, yes! This is a special day!
Yeah! 1st anniversary all of a sudden!
1st anniversary! I can't believe it's 1 year already together with you guys and with Advent!
Yes! Advent's 1st year all together! Advent's 1st year together went so fast!
And we'll have many more years! Yeah! Aww!
Thank you so much Advenders for always being here during our silly times playing this and that game all together!
All the gnomes! The gnomes!
And when we release special original songs and accomplish stuff!
And we're looking forward to all the new heights that hopefully we'll be able to reach together with you!
And on final request, you know... Let's keep aiming for the stars!
Yeah! We're gonna grow taller!
We're gonna grow tall!
Speaking of the next star...
How about we present our new original song,
Spotlight!
Yeah! Let's go!
Spotlight
[Title: Spotlight]
Get the mics, hit the lights, Race ya to the stage!
Check, one, two! Now we're on the way—
Take a deep breath, this is our moment
We can make it, we're chasin' after greatness
Watch the curtain rise (goin' up, goin' up)
Feel electrified (never stop, never stop)
Mm, we got that vibe, yeah, you know that's right
Gotta keep it hype, it's our time!
No more fear (feel alive)
I'm right here (by your side)
Cue me in and let the music play, take it away!
Steal a little spotlight (spotlight!)
I wanna see you shine bright (shine bright!)
Now you're ready for the big time (big time!)
Raise up your voice, it's all right
Steal a little spotlight (spotlight!)
It hits ya like a bullseye (Bullseye!)
You gotta chase it for your whole life (Whole life!)
So run with all of your might to the spotlight
Play that rhythm, they won't know what hit 'em
Gonna be unforgettable, so much fun, it's criminal
We keep plotting to steal the show, oh yeah
On your mark and ready, set, GO! GO!
Oh, we never miss (What a bop, what a bop)
Yeah, we're lovin' this (Keep it up, keep it up)
Take it all in, this is who we are in the dark
(We shine like stars)
No more tears (Here we are)
Feel those cheers (In your heart)
Let the whole world know it's you and me, finally free!
Steal a little spotlight (Spotlight!)
I wanna see you shine bright (Shine bright!)
Now you're ready for the big time (Big time!)
Raise up your voice, it's all right
Steal a little spotlight (Spotlight!)
It hits ya like a bullseye (Bullseye!)
You gotta chase it for your whole life (Whole life!)
So run with all of your might
Steal that spotlight
Aura farming baddies in a getaway car
Rizz 'em up and never stop, gonna be stars
Breakin' out, breakin' rules, joking like it's April Fool's
Ooh...
Like a moth to a flame
You been caught, welcome to our game
It's your move, wanna play?
You're confused, goin' renegade?
Advent, yeah, that's right
Advent, steal that spotlight!
Life's sweeter on the run, just having fun
One, two, three, four!
Steal a little spotlight (Spotlight!)
I wanna see you shine bright (Shine bright!)
Now you're ready for the big time (Big time!)
Raise up your voice, it's all right
Steal a little spotlight (Spotlight!)
It hits ya like a bullseye (Bullseye!)
You gotta chase it for your whole life (Whole life!)
So run with all of your might to the spotlight
Steal the spotlight, steal the spotlight
Now we're really rockin'
Run with all your might...
Steal the spotlight, steal the spotlight
Now I think you got it
Advent! Hey! You like our new song, Spotlight?
Spot, spot, Spotlight!
Big time! We really are aura farming baddies in a getaway car!
Yeah, that's right! Advent! Steal that spotlight!
Wait, wait, wait... I've heard this... this sounds kind of familiar.
No, no, no, no! Don't, don't...
No, this is our original, yeah!
Yeah, yeah, we're senpais! Take that, senpais!
We are the aura farming baddies in a getaway car!
So please listen to Advent's newest song, Spotlight! Lots and lots, okay?
Okey-dokey!
Well, if we can, since we're getting close to the end, maybe we should make some individual announcements!
So I'll start! While we don't have any Advent joint merch, I believe all of us will probably have anniversary merch, and I am no exception!
I think the highlight item this year is a dakimakura! Double-sided with the office lady and my pajama outfit, so please look forward to it!
And then, I've also had a new cover come out recently of a song that we just performed here today, Bad Apple!! in English! So please listen to it!
And Koseki Bijou!
Hey, everyone!
Bijou just released a new VR Chat room, and you might want to check it out cause it's pretty cool! We got a little arcade bar thing going around. Come by and visit! Yeah, yeah, yeah!
And also, Bijou's a little bit close to a million subscribers! So maybe if you could subscribe to my channel, I would be a little happy! So maybe you should subscribe!
Thank you!
And make sure you subscribe and like this video!
Hit the button, hit the button! Hit the bell, the notification button!
The notification button, yeah! Leave a comment below!
Next up!
That's right, FUWAMOCO!
Recently, we released a brand-new original song, "Mekurumeku Rendezvous"!
Also, the ending theme to an anime! So please go check it out!
We also have a big announcement really soon!
Please look forward to that, okay? Okay!
And... Shiori! That's me!
For Shiori Novella of Hololive Advent, I have a mini visual manga series!
The first two episodes are already out!
Nani?
What?
And it has Japanese and Korean subtitles!
And there will be more to come, so please tune in when you can!
Wow, that's it for today! Bye!
Aw, I can't believe it's over already!
Ah, but Advent will continue to go forward together and take next steps!
Please continue to cheer us on, and let's continue this journey, okay?
Huddle time!
Advent strong together? Yes, Advent together strong!
Huddle time! Huddle time! Huddle time!
Advent strong!
Bye-bye!
Okay, come here, come here, come here!
Are you okay?
Bye-bye!